# Anna Mayboroda

## **Software QA Lead Engineer**

Davenport, FL || (407) 728-2155 || mayboroda1985gmail.com|| LinkedIn

#### **SUMMARY**

Detail - oriented **Software QA Lead Engineer** with **7+ years** of hands-on experience in manual testing and automated API testing using Postman with Newman. Skilled with Agile, Scrum Methodologies, tools, and processes in testing of Web-Based Applications. Contribute to all aspects of the testing process: planning, creating test documentation, test execution, defect tracking, and performing testing. Take ownership and deliver results for assigned tasks.Built trusted relationships with the Scrum team by catching issues at the early stage. Strong problem-solving skills, ability to learn new technologies, and excellent attention to detail. **US Citizen.** 

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Linux shell scripting

Cucumber Gherkin **Bug Tracking:** Jira

OS: Windows, macOS, UNIX/Linux, Android OS, iOS

API Testing: REST, Postman, XML, JSON,

Newman, Swagger

Web Testing: Chrome DevTools, HTML, CSS, Xpath

TMS: TestRail, Xray

Teams Collaboration: Confluence, Notion, Slack, Monday.com,

Google Workspace, Miro, Figma

**Database Testing:** SQL, MS SQL Server, MySQL **Mobile Testing;** Android Studio, Xcode

BrowserStack

CI/CD: Git/GitHub, Jenkins, ConcorseCI, Docker

**Methodologies:** Agile, Scrum, TDD, BDD **IDE:** IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse, VSCode, WebStorm

Software: MS Office

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### QA Lead | ChilliPharm, London, UK/ Irvine California, US | Apr 2024 - Present

A (SaaS) company is a secure and compliant Digital Asset Management system used to facilitate quality controls for pharmaceutical trials. It is a multi-tenant system using custom subdomains to allow Trials to have their own portals. It recognizes the critical importance of Information Security, Data Privacy and Good Clinical Practice (GCP), as well as the reliability of data in clinical trials.

- Participate in the release preparation documentation, contribute to continuous integration and delivery processes.
- Support and mentor junior QA engineers for contributing to team growth and expertise.
- Conducted 10+ walkthrough sessions to enhance the teams' product knowledge.
- Review & analysis of quality and completeness of the Requirements, Acceptance Criteria, BRD, Design Mockups and Specifications in line with the shift-left strategy of Agile testing; proactive engagement of Business Analysts and UI/UX Designers.
- Ensured complete regression test coverage by creating, maintaining, and executing over 2000+ Test Cases/scripts in manual format and BDD framework (Cucumber) in VSCode.
- Follow reported defects through resolution with Developers, maintaining a 95% closure rate within timelines.
- Development of Validation Plans, Requirements Traceability Matrix (RTM) and Test Suites of 1000+ Test Cases for complete test coverage in VSCode using Cucumber Gherkin BDD.
- Executed API testing with Newman in VSCode, integrating automated test scripts into the development environment to enhance testing efficiency and coverage.
- Maintain test scripts using Git/GitHub as Version Control and CI/CD tools; participate in peer reviews of test scripts.
- Estimate, prioritize, plan, and coordinate testing activities

### Senior Software QA | ChilliPharm, London, UK | Mar 2023 - Apr 2024

Chillipharm is a leading provider of advanced document management and video solutions for the healthcare and pharmaceutical industries. The company specializes in streamlining the management of clinical trial documentation and regulatory compliance through secure, cloud-based platforms. Their innovative solutions enhance data accuracy, transparency, and operational efficiency, supporting the complexities of clinical research and regulatory requirements.

- Took ownership and deliver results for assigned tasks.
- Reproduced prod defects, analyzed and triaged their root causes using DevTools, and ArgoCD logs, reported, and tracked them in Jira
- Maintain and run tests in Test Automation framework for Web, and REST and using JavaScript, Selenium WebDriver, Cucumber Gherkin BDD, REST Assured, Postman, Swagger, XML, JSON.
- Planned, drafted, and developed Test Documentation: Validation Plans, Test Cases/Test Scripts in BDD and manual format in VSCode.
- Performed functional testing, regression testing, UAT, usability testing, migration, system, and integration testing.
- Collaborate closely with cross-functional teams, including developers and product managers, to identify, prioritize, and resolve quality issues, leading to faster bug resolution and improved communication.

- Monitored automation results and manually replicated failed Test Cases.
- Attended all Scrum meetings and prioritize issues during Grooming sessions.

#### Software QA Engineer | ChilliPharm, London, UK | Apr 2020 - Mar 2023

IT leading global provider of cloud-based image/video management for end-point outcome measures in clinical trials.

- Decreased the number of prod defects by fleshing out the edge case scenarios at an early stage
- Decrease time in Manual Testing by creating basic API scripts using Postman and run them through Newman
- Conducted black and gray box testing, smoke, integration, regression testing, functional testing, and usability testing.
- Covered API testing using Postman, JSON, XML, Chrome developer tools, and Swagger structure.
- Validated data integrity using SQL scripts (MySQL).
- Ported 300+ Test Cases into Cucumber format providing Xpath information in TFS/Azure DevOps and Jira TestRail.
- Prepared status summary reports.

#### Software QA Engineer | InfomatrixGlobal Inc., Denver, CO | Sep 2017 – Apr 2020

InfoMatrix Global is a technology solutions provider specializing in IT consulting, software development, and digital transformation services. The company delivers innovative solutions across various industries, including healthcare, finance, and manufacturing, with a focus on enhancing operational efficiency and driving business growth. InfoMatrix Global excels in offering custom software development, IT infrastructure management, and strategic consulting to address complex business challenges and optimize technology investments.

- Improved product quality by making recommendations for testing process.
- Partnered with the dev team in debugging process and issue escalation.
- Design and execute Test Cases in VSCode using Gherkin language based on user requirements and acceptance criteria.
- Performed testing manually: Acceptance Testing on prod after release and Validation testing before release, as well as Regression, Functional and Non-Functional testing(Exploratory, UX/UI testing, etc).
- Worked closely with Scrum team members to review TMX, FRDS, URS, Test Plans, Test Cases, Feature Tests, SEP Tests

#### **EDUCATION**

**Master's degree, in Finance**, Odessa State Economic University, Odessa, Ukraine. Received evaluation from Josef Silny & Associates Foreign Credential

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

JavaScript for Beginners, Udemy.

Get to Know HTML Learn HTML Basics Get to Know Learn HTML Basics Quick Introduction to postman and API Testing, Udemy
Postman for beginners with practice and exercise, Udemy
Git & GitHub Crash Course Create Repository From Scratch, Udemy
Cucumber, Selenium & Java, Udemy
Advanced Selenium WebDriver with Java and TestNG, Udemy
Selenium WebDriver with Java for beginners, Udemy
XPath locators for Selenium, Udemy
MasterClass Software Testing with Jira & Agile -Be a QA Lead, Udemy
Agile With Scrum - From Beginner to Advanced, Udemy

## **LANGUAGES**

<u>Ukrainian</u>

<u>Russian</u>